These are lies you can say in a job interview. At least that's what it feels like when you're the one saying them. Because what I'm going to share are the moments where your honest answer could hurt you, even though it shouldn't. And the version you give instead, it's not fake. It's what everyone in hiring expects you to say. But if no one's ever told you that, it can feel like you're being dishonest. I spent over a decade on the other side of the hiring table at
Google, Tik Tok, Uber, Lyft, and the New York Times, and I'm going to walk you through all nine of the answers that we expect you to give and why. So, let's get into it. Number one, how are you? This feels like small talk, but it's not. It's an audition that starts before you think it does. I've watched candidates lose momentum in the first 10 seconds of an interview. They'll say something like, "I'm just getting over a cold." or honestly, it's been a rough
week or traffic was a nightmare getting here. And what they don't realize is that I'm already taking a mental note. Not because I'm judging them as a person, but because I'm asking myself, is this how they're going to show up on a hard day at work? You are always great. Always. So, say, I'm great, thank you. How are you? That's it. You're not being fake. You're showing me that you can regulate your energy when it matters. That's a skill. And the interview starts the second you walk
into the room, not when the first real question gets asked. Number two, why do you want to work here? Here's what most people say. I went to your website and I really love your mission and values. That's what everybody says. And I'll tell you what I'm thinking when I hear that. Nothing really. [music] It tells me nothing about you. It tells me that you spent five minutes on our about page. So, what you want to do is flip the question entirely. Stop making it about what you want from them and make it
about what you're going to do for them. Something like, "I've outgrown my current role and I'm looking for a new challenge. And based on what I've seen about this team's goals, I know I can help you solve." And then insert the problem. You're not there to take, you are there to contribute. And here's the mindset shift. Stop treating interviews like auditions where you're hoping to be chosen. Treat them like a meeting between two parties who both have something to offer. That energy shift,
hiring managers can feel it immediately. Number [music] three, where do you see yourself in 5 years? Let me tell you what we're actually asking because it's not about your five-year plan. We don't actually care about your five-year plan. What we want to know are two things. One, are you going to leave in six months? And two, are your goals aligned with this role? Or are you going to get bored and become a problem? Which is why you never say I'm going to grad school. Never say starting my own business.
Never say hopefully in a leadership role somewhere. Because somewhere tells me probably not here. Even if those things are true, and they might be, that's not what we want to hear in this moment. What we need to hear is, "I see myself here. I see myself becoming an expert in this area and I'm a valuable part of this team." This role aligns with where I want to go because, and then you connect it to something specific about the job. You're not lying about who you are. You're telling the version of the
truth that serves this conversation. There's [music] a difference. Number four, why are you looking for a new opportunity? This is for when you're employed. We don't want to hear that you hate your boss or that your company is toxic, that you're being micromanaged or underpaid or undervalued. Even if every word of it is true, especially if it's true, that's not what you say. And here's why. When you trash a current employer, I'm not thinking, "Oh, that sounds terrible." Instead, I'm thinking,
what is she going to say about us in two years? You become a risk. And in a stack of qualified candidates, risks get cut. So, keep it clean. Say, "I've learned a lot in my current role, and now I'm ready for a new challenge." Done. You said nothing negative. You've shown growth and you moved the conversation forward. One sentence, move on. Number five, how do you feel about your current manager? Now, this is different from the last one, and here's why. Because it needs to be its own point, because
sometimes the person interviewing you is about to become your next boss, and that changes everything. I've watched this happen in real time. A candidate was interviewing for a role on a team that I was recruiting for, and she mentioned that her current manager was a quote micromanager and too hands-on, and that she was looking for more autonomy. The hiring manager nodded politely, said nothing, but that hiring manager was known internally for being heavily involved in her team's work. Some people
loved it, some people didn't, but the candidate had just told her without realizing it that her management style was a problem. She didn't get the offer, and she never really knew why. Say nothing negative about your current boss, nothing about your co-workers, nothing about leadership ever, because you don't know who you're talking to, and you don't know who they know. This isn't about being fake. It's about not handing someone a reason to say no. So instead of saying, "He's a
micromanager," you could say, "My manager has been great at providing structure for our team's goals. I've learned a lot about process from him and as I've grown, I've become more proactive in anticipating next steps and I'm excited about the possibility of bringing that proactive energy to a new team. Number six, [music] your hobbies. Now, this one's going to surprise you because most people just treat this as a throwaway, but it's not. I once had a candidate mention that she was restoring
a vintage motorcycle in her garage. She wasn't interviewing for anything mechanical. It was a marketing role, but that detail made her memorable. It signaled curiosity, patience, willingness to figure things out, and the hiring manager brought it up three times in the debrief. On the other end, I've had candidates tell me their main hobby is watching TV or hanging out with friends. And there's nothing wrong with that. We all do it, but it doesn't give me anything to work with. So instead,
you become forgettable. You're not listing activities. Instead, you're painting a picture of who you are when you're not at work. And the picture should make someone think, "Huh, that's interesting. I'd want to get coffee with that person." Reading, hiking, learning a new language, building something, mentoring, playing in a sports league. Those are examples of things that you can say. [music] And these tell me that you're curious, engaged, and you have a life outside of work. Pick the version
of yourself that's true and memorable. So, instead of saying, "I like Netflix and going out," you could say, "Outside of work, I'm an avid home baker. I actually run a small Instagram page where I document my attempts to mastering sourdough. It's taught me a lot about patience, process, and troubleshooting when things don't rise as expected." Number seven, your job title and description. This is the one that trips up high performers the most, and I need you to hear me on this. If you've been
doing the work above your pay grade, you need to claim it. If you've been leading projects without the official title, you can say that you led them. If you've been doing the job of a senior person while being paid as a junior one, own the job. I've reviewed hundreds of thousands of résumés, and one of the most common mistakes I see is people underelling what they've actually done because they're waiting for permission. They're waiting for the promotion, the title change, the official recognition,
and in the meantime, they're letting other candidates take credit for the level of work they're already doing. [music] The title on your badge is what HR decided. The work you've done is what actually matters. And if you don't articulate that clearly, someone with less experience, but more confidence is going to walk in and take the job that you were qualified for. That's not lying. that's accurately representing the value that you created. So for example, if your title is marketing
coordinator, but you led the campaign, you could say, "While my title was marketing coordinator, I was responsible for leading the Q3 email campaign from concept to execution." This involves setting the strategy, coordinating the design and copy, analyzing the AB test results, and presenting the 15% lift in engagement to leadership. Number eight, resume gaps. This one stresses people out way more than it should. And here's what I want you to understand. That gap on your resume already got you the
interview. We saw it. We still called you. Which means we've already decided that it's not a deal breakaker. You just need to not make it weird. If you went back to school, got a certification, or did volunteer work, talk about what you learned and how it applies to the job you're [music] interviewing for. If you were laid off, say that there were layoffs. I've been laid off. It happens. We understand. If it was something personal like health, family, caregiving, you can simply say, "I took
time off for personal reasons and now I'm ready to return to work." In the US, employers legally can't ask you about your family status and won't push. Here's what actually matters. The energy that you bring when you talk about it. If you're defensive or apologetic, I'm going to sense that something's wrong. If you're matterof-act and confident, I'm going to move on. The gap isn't the problem. How you handle it is. For example, let's say you had a 9-month gap
for caregiving. You could say in your interview, "I took a planned period away from my career to focus on a family commitment. During that time, I kept my skills sharp by completing a Google Analytics certification and doing some freelance content work. I'm now fully ready and eager to return to a full-time role where I can contribute deeply. And say this with a calm, confident tone. Number nine, do you have any questions for us? Do not say, "No, I think you covered everything." That's the fastest
way to end an interview on a flat note. [music] And here's what it actually communicates to me. You're not that interested. You haven't thought beyond today, and you're just trying to get through this. The questions you ask tell me how you think. They tell me whether you're already picturing yourself in this role or just hoping to survive the conversation. Have at least two questions ready. Why is this position open is a good one. And it tells you if someone got promoted, quit, or was
fired. And that's useful information for you. What does success look like in the first 90 days? This question shows that you're already thinking about how to deliver. Don't ask about vacation days or remote work flexibility in the first interview. That's a negotiation conversation, not an interview conversation. The best candidates ask questions that make the interviewer think that's what you're aiming for. For example, don't say no. Instead, ask, [music] "You mentioned the team is
growing. Could you describe the dynamic between this role and the team it collaborates with the most closely?" Or you could ask, based on our conversation today, what would you say is the most immediate challenge the person in this role would need to tackle in their first month? Interviews aren't about being the most honest person in the room. They're about being the most strategic. Same person, same skills, different answers. Now, if you've been laid off, check out this video where I lay out a 10-day plan
to get you back on your